# Johnny Perez

787-218-1432 johnnypr@iastate.edu

#### **PROFILE**

My name is Johnny Perez and I am majoring in Biology at Iowa State with goals of entering medical school. In my introductory and upper-level coursework, I have developed a passion for science and am extremely interested in pursuing independent research as an undergraduate, opportunities for self development and leadership by the helping of others.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Secretary, JPR Accounting, Ponce, Puerto Rico 2014-2015

Perform clerical activities, such as answering phones, sorting mail, filing, typing, word processing, and photocopying and mailing out material.

# Food Preparation, Hawthorn Dining, Ames, Iowa 2017-2017

Measure ingredients required for specific food items being prepared.

# Researcher, Microbiology Lab, Ames, Iowa 2017-2018

Provide laboratory services for health departments, for community environmental health programs and for physicians needing information for diagnosis and treatment. Isolate and maintain cultures of bacteria or other microorganisms in prescribed or developed media, controlling moisture, aeration, temperature, and nutrition.

#### **EDUCATION**

Caribbean School, Ponce, Puerto Rico — GED, Graduation-2015

University of Puerto Rico, Mayaguez, Puerto Rico — College Course Work.

Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa—On going Biology Bachelor- 2020

## **EXTRACURRICULARS**

Mentoring Chairman of Minority Association for Pre-Health Students at Iowa State Mentor students in order to apply to professional school. Plan social events in order for students to network with future colleagues. Provide students with information about resources available to underrepresented or underserved communities in order for them to have access to opportunities. Work with other cabinet members to bring in health professionals to mentor and inspire students.

#### **SKILLS**

- Preparing and delivering presentations
- Communication of knowledge to others

- · Report writing
- Interpersonal skills
- · Leadership and team skills
- Data collection and analysis
- Time management
- Problem solving
- Proficiency in General and Organic Chemistry
- Coding (Python and Javascript)

#### **SCIENCE COURSEWORK:**

- General Biology I & II
  - Labs included
- General Chemistry I & II
  - · Labs included
- Organic Chemistry I & II
  - · Labs included
- Microbiology
- Molecular Cell Biology
- Neuroscience
  - · Labs included
- Physics I
  - · Labs included
- Molecular Genetics

#### ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- 75+ Hours Community Service
- Ponce School of Medicine Pathology Internship
- P.A. Assistantship opportunity in Hospital Damas, Ponce Puerto Rico

•